A Guide to the Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Correspondence and subject files, 1994-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files, 1994-1997
Library of Virginia
35873
3.35 cubic feet
Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 22 June 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
The office of the Secretary of Commerce and Resources was established in 1972 and was responsible for the areas of economic development and natural resources. In 1986 this secretariat was dissolved and split into two separate offices, the Secretary of Economic Development and the Secretary of Natural Resources. In 1994 the name of the office was changed from the Secretary of Economic Development to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.
The Secretary of Commerce and Trade is appointed by the governor and serves as a member of his cabinet. The Secretary of Commerce and Trade's chief responsibility is to manage the direction of several state agencies that are concerned with the development of commerce and economic development throughout the Commonwealth. Agencies reporting to the Secretary of Commerce and Trade include: Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services; Department of Business Assistance; Department of Economic Development; Department of Labor and Industry; Department of Mines, Minerals, and Energy; Virginia Employment Commission; Virginia Housing Development Authority; Department of Professional and Occupational Regulations; Department of Housing and Community Development; Milk Commission; Department of Minority Business Enterprise; Department of Forestry; Virginia Racing Commission; Virginia Resources Authority; and the Virginia Tourism Corporation.
Robert T. Skunda was appointed Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade by Governor Governor George Allen in December 1993. Secretary Skunda, a native of Michigan, graduated from the University of Michigan with a BA in Architecture and an MA in Urban Planning. Secretary Skunda is a past president of the Fairfax County Chamber of Commerce and past chairman of the Virginia Chamber of Commerce. Directly prior to being appointed Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Skunda was managing principal in the architectural and engineering planning firm of Dewberry and Dove. Robert Skunda resigned as Secretary of Commerce and Trade November 1, 1997, when he was appointed president and chief executive officer of the Virginia Biotechnology Research Park.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade are organized into the following series: I. Correspondence of the Secretary, 1994-1997; II. Opportunity Virginia, 1994-1997; III. Base Retention and Defense Adjustment (BRADA), 1994-1996; and IV. Community Development Block Grants, 1994-1997.
Series I. Correspondence of the Secretary, 1994 Jan-1997 Oct. This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence on a variety of subjects. Arranged chronologically.
Series II. Opportunity Virginia, 1994-1997. This series contains records documenting Governor George Allen's Opportunity Virginia initiative and includes correspondence, reference files, press releases, speeches, meeting records, maps, newsletters, videos, reports and studies related to ecomonic development. The initiative was launched to promote economic growth and prosperity across the Commonwealth of Virginia. Arranged by subject or economic development region.
Series III. Base Retention and Defense Adjustment (BRADA) Commission, 1994-1996. This series contains records documenting the role of the Commonwealth of Virginia in potential military base closings within the state, and includes correspondence, reference files, reports, memoranda, meeting records, and state and federal publications pertaining to defense installation conversion and economic adjustment for affected sites. Arranged by subject.
Series IV. Community Development Block Grants, 1994-1997. This series documents grants for community improvements administered by the Dept. of Housing and Community Development. Includes grant applications, correspondence, approval letters, press releases and other related materials. Arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence of the Secretary, 1994 Jan-1997 Oct
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1994 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Mar (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Apr (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Jun (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Jul (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Aug (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Sep (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Oct (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Nov (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Dec (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Jan (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Feb (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Mar (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Apr (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1995 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Jun (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Jul (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Aug (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Sep (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Oct (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Nov (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Dec (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Jan (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Feb (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Mar (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Apr (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1996 May (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Jun (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Jul (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Aug (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Sep (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Oct (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Nov (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Dec (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Jan (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Feb (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Mar (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Apr (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1997 May (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Jun (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Jul (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Aug (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Sep (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1997 Oct (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Series II. Opportunity Virginia, 1994-1997
  Arranged by subject.
  - Opportunity Virginia: Executive Order and Press Releases, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Speech, 1995 Jan 7 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Press Kit information, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Presentation, 1994 Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Steering Committee materials, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Plan Distribution, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Opportunity Virginia: REDAC maps, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Work plans, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Newsletters, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Video Tour, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Opportunity Virginia: REDAC Chairpersons - Mailing lists and letters, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Opportunity Virginia: General Assembly and other relevant studies, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Research, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 1, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 2, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 3, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 7, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 9, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 10, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 11, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 12, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 13, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 15, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 16, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 17, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Correspondence - Region 18, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Opportunity Virginia: Video, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Series III: Base Retention and Defense Adjustments (BRADA) Commission, 1994-1996
  - BRADA: Governor Allen's Tour of Hampton Roads Military Installations, 1994 Jun 17 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - BRADA: Office of Economic Adjustment Conference - Defense Industry Cutbacks - Communities in Transition, 1994 Apr 6-7 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - BRADA: Office of Economic Adjustment Conference - Defense Industry Cutbacks - Communities in Transition, 1994 Apr 6-7 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - BRADA: Office of Economic Adjustment Conference - Defense Industry Cutbacks - Communities in Transition, 1994 Apr 6-7 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - BRADA: Office of Economic Adjustment Conference - Defense Industry Cutbacks - Communities in Transition, 1994 Apr 6-7 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - BRADA: Naval Air Station Oceana Tour, 1994 Oct 21 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - BRADA: Visit/Briefing Fort Eustis, Naval Weapons Station - Yorktown and Norfolk Naval Shipyard, 1994 Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - BRADA: Visit/Briefing Fort Lee, Defense General Supply Center, and Defense Distribution Depot Richmond, 1995 Jan 23 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - BRADA: Committee meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - BRADA: Commission meetings - minutes and attachments, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - BRADA: U.S. Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission Regional Hearing, Baltimore, MD, 1995 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - BRADA: Virginia Military Insatllations Background Information, 1995 Feb (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - BRADA: Visit/Briefing Fort Lee, Defense General Supply Center, and Defense Distribution Depot Richmond, 1995 Jan 23 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - BRADA: Information pertaining to Fort Lee visit, 1995 Jan 23 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - BRADA: Community Response to proposed base closings - Kenner Army Community Hospital, 1995 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - BRADA: Background and Committee information, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - BRADA: Committee briefings, notes and memoranda, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - BRADA: Committee briefings, notes and memoranda, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - BRADA: Defense Conversions Initiatives, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - BRADA: Directory of Federal Reinvestment Initiative for People, Business, and Communities, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - BRADA: Adjusting to the Drawdown - Federal publication concerning defense conversion, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - BRADA: Governor's Guide to Economic Conversion, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - BRADA: A Profile of Defense Procurement Spending in Virginia, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - BRADA: Virginia Military Advisory Council (VMAC) - Meeting, 1995 May 30 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - BRADA: Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment - Report, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - BRADA: Assorted publications from the Virginia Employment Commissio concerning defense conversion and economic adjustment, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - BRADA: Industrial Modernization and Extension Service Information - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - BRADA: Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - BRADA: Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - BRADA: The Northern Virginia Regional Alliance - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - BRADA: Listing of Virginia's Prime Defense Contractors - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - BRADA: Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment - Report, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - BRADA: Proceedings from the Governor's Conference on Defense Conversion, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - BRADA: Army Basing Study on Base Closure and Realignment - COBRA reports, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - BRADA: Department of the Army - Installation narratives, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - BRADA: Department of the Army - Analyses and recommendations, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - BRADA: New Technology Reinvestment Project Proposal (TRP), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - BRADA: Defense General Supply Center (DGSC) - Information, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - BRADA: Fort Lee, Petersburg - Information, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - BRADA: Guidebook to Federal Programs - publication, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - BRADA: Closure history - Installations in Virginia, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - BRADA: Fort Lee - BRAC brief, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - BRADA: Governor's Commission on Defense Conversion and Economic Adjustment - Final report, 1994 Jan (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - BRADA: Governor's Conference on Defense Conversion, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 116)
- Series IV: Community Development Block Grants, 1994-1997
  - Community Development Block Grants, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Community Development Block Grants, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Community Development Block Grants, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Community Development Block Grants, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 120)